Department of Mechanical Engineering Records UA051
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Department of Mechanical Engineering Records
1949 -- 2006
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
School of Engineering
Department of Mechanical Engineering
UA051
1.7 Linear Feet 2 boxes
Arrangement
This collection is organized in five series: Annual reports; Brochures; Program and course booklets; and Graduate thesis abstracts; and Unprocessed accessions.
Biographical / Historical
The Department of Mechanical Engineering was created in 1894-1895 as part of the the Tufts College of Engineering. At that time, the College of Engineering consisted only of the Departments of Civil and Electrical Engineering. A Ph.D. program was added to the Department of Mechanical Engineering in 1963.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains annual reports, brochures, program and course booklets, and graduate thesis abstracts documenting the Department of Mechanical Engineering's outreach, advancement, and recruitment activities.
Curriculum and Instruction -- Academic Departments and Programs; Curriculum and Instruction -- Student Work
- Annual Reports, 1974 -- 2003; 1975 -- 2003; UA051.001; 1.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  These annual reports provide information on the faculty, publications, course offerings, and student statistics. The annual reports were generated by the department annually for review. There are missing years in this series.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Annual Report, 1974 -- 1975; UA051.001.001.00001; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1975 -- 1976; UA051.001.001.00002; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1977 -- 1978; UA051.001.001.00003; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1980 -- 1981; UA051.001.001.00004; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1981 -- 1982; UA051.001.001.00005; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1982 -- 1983; UA051.001.001.00006; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1983 -- 1984; UA051.001.001.00007; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1984 -- 1985; UA051.001.001.00008; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1985 -- 1986; UA051.001.001.00009; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1988 -- 1989; UA051.001.001.00010; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1990 -- 1991; UA051.001.001.00011; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1992 -- 1993; UA051.001.001.00012; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1993 -- 1994; UA051.001.001.00013; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1994 -- 1995; UA051.001.001.00014; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1995 -- 1996; UA051.001.001.00015; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1996 -- 1997; UA051.001.001.00016; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1998 -- 1999; UA051.001.001.00017; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 1999 -- 2000; UA051.001.001.00018; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 2000 -- 2001; UA051.001.001.00019; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 2001 -- 2002; UA051.001.001.00020; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Annual Report, 2002 -- 2003; UA051.001.001.00021; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
- Brochures, UA051.002; 1.2 Linear Feet
  The brochures contain general information about the Mechanical engineering program. The brochures were made for wide distribution.
  This series contains one item.
  - Brochures, UA051.002.001.00022; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
    No Date available
- Program and Course Booklets, 1960 -- 2005; UA051.003; 1.2 Linear Feet
  The Program and Course booklets contain specific information about the courses offered in the Mechanical Engineering department. There are four types of booklets contained in this series. There are Course booklets that contain specific information about course offerings by term and times. There are Undergraduate Program booklets that contain information on undergraduate program requirements for graduation. There are Graduate Program booklets that contain information on graduate program requirements for graduation. There are Human Factor; Mechanical engineering and Psychology Program Booklets that contain information about this dual degree program and requirements.
  - Program Booklet, 1960; UA051.003.001.00023; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1961; UA051.003.001.00024; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1962; UA051.003.001.00025; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1964; UA051.003.001.00026; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1965; UA051.003.001.00027; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1966; UA051.003.001.00028; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Undergraduate Program Booklet, 1968; UA051.003.001.00029; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Undergraduate Program Booklet, 1971; UA051.003.001.00030; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1972; UA051.003.001.00031; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1973; UA051.003.001.00032; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1976; UA051.003.001.00033; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1977; UA051.003.001.00034; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1980; UA051.003.001.00035; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1982; UA051.003.001.00036; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1986; UA051.003.001.00037; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1987; UA051.003.001.00038; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1988; UA051.003.001.00039; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Booklet, 1989; UA051.003.001.00040; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program Requirements Booklet, 1992; UA051.003.001.00041; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program and Course Booklets, 2001 -- 2002; UA051.003.001.00042; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program and Course Booklets, 2002 -- 2003; UA051.003.001.00043; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program and Course Booklets, 2003 -- 2004; UA051.003.001.00044; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
  - Program and Course Booklets, 2004 -- 2005; UA051.003.001.00045; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
- Graduate Thesis Abstracts, 2004; 2003 -- 2004; UA051.004; 1.2 Linear Feet
  The abstracts are from the completed mechanical engineering graduate thesis and PhD dissertations. Each year, all of the abstracts are bound together for presentation purposes.
  - Graduate Thesis Abstracts, 2004; UA051.004.001.00046; Department of Mechanical Engineering (Box UA051 Shared 1)
- Additional accessions, 1949 -- 2009; UA051.005
  - Annual Report, thesis abstracts, course offerings, information booklets, plus Final Report released 1949., 1949 -- 2006; UA051-001 (Box data_value_missing_0e581fb011c4efd91660684b08069c61, Box 1)